[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Apocalypse Log 16]
Where did you go?
I just went to the canteen.
I was afraid the food would run out.
It's okay, I'm not hungry.
Give it to Grandma Qiu and the others.
Granny Qiu.
He Yao, what are you doing?
Stop fighting! Lie, stop!
Are you crazy?
Dr. He is treating Granny Qiu's injury.
You liar!
How dare you show up here?
You...
Foolish!
You two fools!
Dr. He is helping me.
I was moving things just now and wasn't careful.
I dislocated my shoulder.
It hurts like hell.
Dr. He is resetting it for me.
How can you hit someone without even asking what's going on?
I'm fine.
Calm down, everyone.
It's just a misunderstanding.
Granny Qiu.
Try moving your shoulder.
Is it okay now?
Yes.
It's better.
Thank you, Dr. He.
It's nothing.
I have a bit of a...
small misunderstanding with them.
You two.
Let's talk over there.
Don't fight.
Talk things out calmly.
Don't worry, Grandma.
Why did you steal our car?
It was an emergency. I had to leave.
And I didn't want to involve you.
Fine.
I admit that what I did was wrong.
Lin Zai, I'm sorry.
But I really didn't mean to harm you.
Then why are you here?
Don't tell me it's another coincidence.
I couldn't find my brother.
I drove here, and bumped into Dao and the others.
So, I'm staying at this camp for now.
Where's the car?
The car is right in the back.
I'll take you there.
Let's just move on from this, all right?
Whether we move on is up to me.
When did you get injured?
It's nothing, just a minor wound.
Don't move. The wound is so deep.
Why didn't you say anything?
Now, lead the way to the car.
What tricks are you trying to pull now?
I'll take you there.
You can have it back.
It's out of fuel.
I didn't even notice.
There's actually a barrel of fuel here.
This must be the camp's reserve fuel.
It's an important resource.
We shouldn't just use it like this.
Lin Zai is right.
It belongs to someone else, after all.
Do you even have a say in this?
Lie, watch your tone.
This fuel already has an owner.
Besides, we're not in a hurry to leave.
Are you not in a hurry to leave,
or do you just not want to come with me?
What do you mean by that?
If you're in such a hurry, then leave by yourself.
Lin Zai!
Chang Huan, I met someone.
He's just like you.
His wounds heal at an astonishing rate,
but he shows no signs of turning.
I suspect it's an abnormal evolution
that occurs after resisting the zombie virus.
I'll do whatever it takes to keep him here.
If he is an immune body,
our experiment will surely succeed.
The three of you...
didn't have further conflict, did you?
Dr. He doesn't seem like a bad person to me.
The misunderstanding is cleared up.
It's fine.
Dr. He... is a bit of a loner,
but he's a good man.
You young people...
You're being too rough.
Don't hurt Grandma.
All right.
I feel better after moving around.
You two must be tired.
Go back and get some rest.
It's okay, Grandma.
I'll walk you back.
Let's go.
We're in luck today.
Caught a little something.
I'll clean them up in a bit.
I'll add some fresh flavor for everyone.
Take a look.
Great! We haven't had meat in ages.
Sir, can I have this sand crab?
- This one? - Yes.
It's so small, there's no meat.
What do you want it for?
Just let me have it.
Give it to him.
All right, it's yours.
In a while, I'll finish cleaning and make a stew.
I'll improve the rations for everyone tonight.
- Sound good? - Yeah!
Lin Zai.
This is for you.
I remember you like these.
I don't need it.
Take it away.
It's a gift.
The apocalypse has taken a lot from me.
So, I want to cherish the people I meet,
people I can rely on.
I think we could become companions who are like family.
Used to being abandoned.
Discarding others to save yourself...
Isn't that just human instinct?
I'm not like them.
I have a heart.
I will protect you...
with my life.
Thank you.
Go back.
So, are you still mad at me?
I'm not mad at you.
- Then why... - Too much has happened lately.
My mind is a bit of a mess.
I need to clear my head first.
You should go.
Come in.
I just prepared some herbs.
I'm taking them to Grandma Qiu.
I thought I'd stop by and see you.
You have a pet?
I found it on the road.
A sand crab.
It's quite lively.
Yeah.
In this environment,
I'll keep it alive as long as I can.
By the way, weren't you interested in my research before?
I asked Dao to get some equipment,
and set up a simple lab.
Do you want to take a look?
Now?
Yeah, if it's convenient for you.
It's not far, just next door.
Okay.
Come in.
Is this all your lab equipment?
Scavenged from all over.
Dao and his men salvaged most of it from various medical sites.
It's a mismatched collection.
It's good enough that it works.
What's in here?
Don't be afraid.
This is a subject I asked Dao to help me capture.
He helps with this too?
Researching a vaccine is a good cause.
Of course he'd help out.
Brother...
This is my brother, He Yao.
This... This is your brother?
- Yes. - Are you sure?
Yes, it's him.
What will you do to him?
If we were at Casia,
his blood and cerebrospinal fluid would be drawn.
Some tissues or organs would be removed
for in vitro cultivation.
- Or... - Enough!
I won't let you do that to him.
Don't be nervous.
What I just described
is Casia's standard experimental procedure.
But I won't do that.
What do you mean?
What I really want to research
has never been a vaccine.
It's antiretroviral drugs.
A cure to turn zombies back into humans.
What? Say that again.
My research direction
runs counter to the goals of Casia's higher-ups.
They believe researching a zombie cure
would cause confusion regarding the identity of zombies,
and lead to an uncontrollable moral collapse.
So, I was forbidden from doing such research
and was even put under surveillance.
So, I ran away.
Simply put, Casia doesn't see zombies as humans.
But I do.
Come with me.
Is it true?
You can make a cure?
No, I can't.
At least not yet.
Why not?
- Isn't all this... - This vial of test fluid
was synthesized using everything I could get my hands on back then.
But the results are extremely unstable
and cannot be replicated.
The key problem is, I'm missing a specific antibody
that can neutralize and reverse the virus.
Theoretically, this antibody is most likely
to be found in a very small number of cases
who have been infected with the virus
but have not turned into zombies.
I was bitten by a zombie.
But I didn't mutate.
Do I have this antibody in my body?
You... You're an immune.
Yes. I'm an immune.
Can you make a cure now?
Yes.
I can.
I'm sure I can.
I can help you with the experiment.
But you have to swear...
that you'll turn my brother back into a human.
Okay. I swear.
But you must understand...
the experimental process
comes with unpredictable risks.
It might cause you harm.
Some of it might even be irreversible.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
Good.
You must not let anyone know about this.
This fuel already belongs to someone.
Besides, we're not in a hurry to leave.
Are you not in a hurry to leave,
or do you just not want to come with me?
Is it possible that one day,
zombies could turn back into humans?
A zombie is a zombie.
They can't turn back.
Okay.